technogym.com 2017-06-03

# Privacy Policy & Cookies | Technogym | Technogym

**Privacy Policy**

Table of contents

  * **Data controller**

  * **Type of data processed**

  * **Purpose and methods of the data processing operations.**
  * **Mandatory or optional nature of data provision and the consequences of refusal.**
  * **Subjects or categories of subjects to which the personal data may be disclosed or who may come to acquire knowledge thereof, in their capacity as data processing controllers or persons charged with data processing and the scope of disclosure of the above-mentioned data.**
  * **Rights of the data subject. The personal details of the data controller and, if appointed, the person charged with processing the data. Indication of the methods by which the updated list of data processors can be readily accessed.**

This notice is issued pursuant to Article 13 of Legislative Decree 196/2003, The Personal Data Protection Code (herein: “ **The Privacy Code** ”), containing indications as to the regulations and directives with which Technogym complies with regard to the processing of personal data of users of the company website [www.technogym.com](http://www.technogym.com/) (“ **the Site** ”)

  * **Data controller**

The data controller is Technogym S.p.A. (herein: “ **Technogym** ”), with registered offices in Via Calcinaro no. 2861, 47521 Cesena (FC), Italy.

  * **Type of data processed**

_Browsing data_  
The information systems and _software_ procedures used to operate the Site acquire, during the course of normal operation, some personal data, the transmission of which is implicit in Internet communication protocols.

This concerns information that is not collected expressly to be associated with specific individuals, but which, by its very nature, could allow users to be identified, through the processing and association with data held by third parties.

This category of data includes IP addresses or domain names of computers used by users who connect to the Site, _URI (Uniform Resource Identifier_ ) addresses of the resources requested, the time of the request, the method used in order to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the response from the _server_ (successful, error, etc.) and other parameters relating to user operating system and virtual environment.

This data is exclusively used to obtain anonymous statistical information regarding Site use, and to check that the latter is functioning correctly; it is deleted immediately after processing. The data may also be used to ascertain responsibility in case of hypothetical computer crimes against the Site: with the exception of this possibility, the data on _web_ contacts are not stored for more than seven days.

_Data provided voluntarily by the user_  
Data freely, explicitly and voluntarily provided by user by sending emails to the addresses listed on the Site entails the subsequent acquisition of the sender's email address, which is necessary to answer any queries, as well as of any other personal information included in the message.

Specific summary information will be provided or displayed on the Site pages as an when appropriate at each stage with regard to specific services available on request.

_Interaction with social networks_

Users with a Facebook profile can register on the site by clicking on the "Login with Facebook" button. In such cases, Facebook automatically sends certain user data to Technogym, as specified in the "pop-up" window that appears at the time of the request; the user is not required to complete any other forms.

**_Cookies_**  
Information regarding the cookies used by Technogym can be found at the following link:[Cookie Policy](http://www.technogym.com/us/cookie-policy/)

  * **Purpose and methods of the data processing operations.**

Technogym informs site users that the data collected will be used exclusively for the purposes stipulated below, with specific consent where necessary:

a) in order to comply with legal, accounting and tax obligations;

b) in order to carry out contracts of sale for products or contracts of engagement for the provision of services (supply of goods and services);

c) to carry out market research with a view to improving its products or services, and to perform direct marketing activities, via newsletters or via operator telephone calls;

d) to use the information provided by users relating to their motives for requesting our services, with a view to offering them improved service and to being in a position to provide suggestions regarding the products most suited to them (profiling).

  * **Mandatory or optional nature of data provision and the consequences of refusal.**

The provision of data is optional, except in cases in which the details collected are necessary in order to carry out a contract or deliver a service as requested by the user (Letter b). In such cases, refusal to grant access to data will render it impossible for Technogym to carry out this request.

Where the user provides consent for the processing of data for marketing purposes (letter c), he/she may revoke this at any time, even when this refers exclusively to automated contact (email) or indeed to contact via traditional methods (telephone).

Finally, the provision of consent for the processing of data for profiling purposes (letter d) is optional, and absence thereof will not prevent the services requested from being delivered; however, the processing of data to this end is extremely useful, in that it allows the user to receive a more personalised service which is tailored to his/her specific objectives or requirements. Failure to provide consent for the above-mentioned purposes will only allow Technogym to provide a standardised service, and the latter will be unable to take into account the underlying motivations for the user turning to Technogym.

  * **Subjects or categories of subjects to which the personal data may be disclosed or who may come to acquire knowledge thereof, in their capacity as data processing controllers or persons charged with data processing and the scope of disclosure of the above-mentioned data.**

The personal information provided by the user will be disclosed to and used by employees of Technogym and/or its overseas subsidiaries for the sole purpose of carrying out the activities that constitute the reason for which this information was originally collected (for example, to carry out contracts of sale or provision of services or to send out newsletters). The data may be disclosed to the exclusive Technogym distributors and/or other parent companies which are controlled by and/or connected to the Technogym Group in Italy, the EU or countries outside the EU, who will act as autonomous data controllers in compliance with legal provisions concerning the transfer of data to third countries. The data processing activities referred to above are established as necessary in order to properly deliver the service in question to Technogym customers, if located in foreign countries in which Technogym operates, and are therefore permitted under Article. 24, paragraph 1, letter b of the Privacy Code.

Data may also be communicated to suppliers of electronic communication services, banks, financial intermediaries, credit institutions, other financial bodies, managers of centralized IT systems (risk and anti-fraud centres etc.), insurance companies, consultants and freelance professionals who assist Technogym in the recovery of debts and the resolution of disputes, as well as to companies charged with packing, shipping and delivering the purchases or with providing postal and marketing services, duly appointed as data handlers under Article 29 of the Privacy Code. Data may also be disclosed to regulators, research companies or non-profit associations; in this case, information will only be communicated in anonymous form.

  * **Rights of the data subject. The personal details of the data controller and, if appointed, the person charged with processing the data. Indication of the methods by which the updated list of data processors can be readily accessed.**

Pursuant to Article 7 of the Privacy Code,

  1. The data subject has the right to obtain confirmation of the existence or (lack thereof) of personal data concerning him/her, even if this information has not yet been recorded, and is entitled to receive details of this data in intelligible form.
  2. The individual has the right to obtain information in relation to:

a) the origin of this personal data;

b) the purposes and methods of processing;

c) the logic applied in case of processing with the aid of electronic tools;

d) the identity of the data controller, of the person(s) charged with processing the data, and the representatives appointed under article 5, comma 2;

e) Subjects or categories of subjects to which the personal data may be disclosed or who may come to acquire knowledge thereof, in their capacity as designated representatives, data processing controllers or persons charged with data processing within Italian state territory.

3\. The data subject has the right to obtain:

a) updates, corrections or where relevant, additions to the data collected;

b) the deletion, anonymisation or blocking of data processed in violation of the law, including information that does not need to be kept for the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently processed;

c) confirmation that the operations mentioned above in points a) and b), have been made known to those to whom the data was communicated or disclosed, except where this proves impossible or involves the use of means that are clearly disproportionate to the rights being protected. This also applies to the content thereof.

4\. The data subject has the right to object, in whole or in part:

a) to the processing of personal data concerning him/her, even if this information is still relevant to the scope of the collection, for legitimate reasons;

b) to the processing of personal data for the purpose of sending advertising material, for direct sales or for the conduction of market research or commercial communications activities.  
The company Mywellness S.p.A is responsible for processing the data, granted for the management of the service platform Mywellnesscloud, provided by Technogym. The updated list of the individuals responsible for data processing can be obtained by sending a request to the data controller at legal@technogym.com.

To exercise the above rights, data subjects may contact the data controller at the postal address provided, or alternatively by sending an email to [legal@technogym.it](mailto:legal@technogym.it)
